Christopher Hedlund

Prospect Park, PA 19076 | chris284891@gmail.com | 443.417.3490

<u>LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/2NeG8sW</u> | <u>GitHub: https://github.com/chris284891</u> | <u>Portfolio: https://chris284891.github.io/Portfolio/</u>

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for front-end development. Experience building websites with Javascript, MySQL, and jQuery from start to finish and seeing strong outcomes when deploying. Adapts well to diverse working environments and collaborating with teams. Bring experience obtained through meticulous design. Prepared to excel in solving complex problems.

SKILLS

Web Development: Express.js, React.js, JavaScript ES5/ES6, Handlebars.js, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Heroku,

Bootstrap, Sequelize

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, FireBase, Google Cloud Storage

Miscellaneous: Windows, Git/Github, Google API, Spotify API, Google Sheets, Google Suite, Microsoft Suite

<u>PROJECTS</u>

MILA: https://github.com/chris284891/MyMilaReactTesting milacaptions.herokuapp.com

- An application that enables users to upload photos and have other users write captions. Users can vote
 for what caption they like the best by giving a gold star or a like on designated photo (Caption creator
 for Instagram)
- **Technologies:** React.js, MondoDB(mLab), Node.js, Express, JavaScript ES6, HTML 5, CSS 3, Firebase, CogoToast, and AOS

My Chef: https://github.com/chris284891/My-Chef | https://chris284891.github.io/My-Chef/

- Javascript application that essentially returns a list of drink or meal recipes based on a given ingredient.
- Technologies: AJAX calls to two seperate API's, JQuery library for "Slick" carousel, and "modal" alerts.

Liri Node App: https://github.com/chris284891/liri-node-app | https://youtu.be/v3Cd6raLesY

- App where the user can search for a song on Spotify, a movie on IMDB, or for a concert on Bandsintown.
- Technologies: JavaScript ES6, Node.js, and NPMs FS, Inquirer, Spotify, Axios, Moment, and Dotenv.

EXPERIENCE

Uber/Caviar Mar. 2015 - Current

Associate/ Driver

U.S. Pools: Jessup, MD Apr. 2011– Mar. 2015

Regional Manager (Philadelphia Area)

- Interacted with clients to ensure quality customer service. And worked with local governmental operations to see that all standards are met.
- Supervised and staffed all swimming pool locations, and provided transportation for foreign visa workers.
- Performed cold calls and sales visits to gain new client contracts.

Pool Supervisor (Baltimore/DC Area)

- Managed the operation of several private community swimming pools located in Greater Baltimore/DC.
- Troubleshoot mechanical problems within pool filtration systems.
- Assisted with pool construction projects and maintenance throughout the winter months.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Bootcamp, Philadelphia, PA

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development

University of Maryland, Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

- Mechanical Engineering and Environmental Science

May 2019 - Oct. 2019

Sept. 2003 - Dec. 2008